

Timo Karsisto
Ratakatu 7 B 13, 00120 Helsinki
+358 50 588 0355
timo.karsisto@gmail.com
28.03.1980

Profile

Timo Karsisto has several years of experience of demanding IT projects as a consultant, specialist, team lead/technical project manager and an architect. He has hands-on experience and broad understanding of various IT technologies. Timo possesses very good communication and coordination skills.

Key Skills

Software engineering methodologies such as RUP, Agile Development (SCRUM); IT architecture and project management methodologies (WWPMM); fluent communication in technical and non-technical subjects; good coordination skills,

Techology

Extensive knowledge of computer networks, infrastructure and operating systems (Windows, Aix/Linux/Unix), security, J2EE technologies such as portals and collaboration technologies, databases, load balancing and high availability solutions.

Comprehensive knowledge of IBM technologies from WebSphere, Lotus, Tivoli and Rational brands.

Professional Experience

IT Specialist, Global Business Services

IBM Oy, Helsinki, Finland January 2007 – present

Experience from over fifteen IT projects in various roles of consultant, specialist, team lead and architect.

Responsible of requirements gathering, analysis and definition; use case modelling; architecture design and implementation; technical and non-technical security consulting; load balancing and high availability architectures; performance testing; security risk analysis; vulnerability and penetration testing; technical project management; bid and proposal work.

IT Specialist (part-time), Global Business Services

IBM Oy, Helsinki, Finland January 2006 – December 2006

Mainly working in enormous SOA project with high security and high availability requirements.

Responsible of security risk analysis, architecture and implementation; design and implementation of load balancing and DNS solutions.

IT Consultant (part-time)

Profides Oy, Helsinki, Finland September 2005 – December 2005

Consulting IT solutions for numerous clients in network, security and infrastructure areas. Responsible of client negotiations, design and implementation phases.

IT Support/Administrator

Wicom Communications Ltd, Espoo, Finland *June 2005 – August 2005*

IT support and administration of workstation and server infrastructure. Responsible of corporate AD, firewalls, Windows, Linux environments and communications with hardware and software vendors.

Data Migration Project

ABB Oy Services, Helsinki, Finland September 2002 – October 2002

Responsible of designing and preparing data for the migration.

Phone and Mobile Phone Matters

ABB Oy Services, Helsinki, Finland June 2002 – September 2002

Responsible of managing department's phone & mobile phone matters and intranet publishing.

Recognitions

IBM, First for the Customer

IBM Finland's recognition for being customer oriented, "first for the customer".

Courses

- -Tivoli Access Manager for e-business 6.0 System Administration
- -Architectural Thinking
- -Project Management Fundamentals

Education

Undergraduate in Natural Sciences, 1999

Etelä-Tapiola High School, Finland

M. Sc in Computer Networks and Work Psychology, 2007

Helsinki University of Technology, Finland

Thesis: Intensifying Information Security Risk Analysis with a Tool

Languages

Finnish (native), English (fluent), Swedish (good)

Military Service

Military Police, Vekaranjärvi, Finland, 1999-2000

References

References are available on request.